# HOLLY MCQUEARY



HMCQUEARYII@GMAIL.COM



352-226-3112



HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/HOLLY-MCQUEARY/



HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/HOLLYGENE

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Driven geneticist experienced in experimental design and protocol development. Highly motivated and a self-starter. Talented in designing experiments, troubleshooting, and developing new protocols. 5+ years of experience managing a research laboratory and training new research assistants.

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### **GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT**

August 2015 - August 2020

- Supervise and train undergraduate research assistants in preparation of media, cleaning of glassware, maintenance of samples, and timeline of experiments
- Organize and maintain records of experimental protocols
- Update and add new experimental protocols as needed
- Submit maintenance requests for lab equipment and organize timing of maintenance
- Oversee maintaining inventory of freezers and lab supply rooms
- Manage inventory and ordering of lab supplies
- Oversee maintenance of lab supplies and cleaning of lab glassware
- Maintain records of orders and safety training of laboratory personnel
- Analyzed and curated short-read NGS genomic sequencing data to identify loss of heterozygosity in diploid mutation accumulation progenitor lines of Saccharomyces cerevisiae
- Produced, curated, and analyzed short-read NGS wholetranscriptome datasets for 45 aneuploid and euploid yeast mutation accumulation lines
- Designed and carried out a 200-day mutation accumulation experiment with 192 individual lines of Saccharomyces paradoxus in order to determine the effect of transposon load on mutation rate and spectrum
- Troubleshooted both wet-lab experiments and data analysis pipelines
- Developed novel protocol for engineering yeast strains to express GFP
- Developed protocol for competitive fitness assays using flow cytometry

### **UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT**

2013 - 2015

Assisted with behavioral studies involving mice

 Handled mice prior to experiments, and injected mice with sodium salicylate to induce tinnitus and examine the effects of treatment on the acoustic startle reflex

#### **SKILLS**

R programming, Python, Linux/Unix, animal models, cell culture, DNA extraction, RNA extraction, genomic library prep, flow cytometry, CRISPR, PCR, primer design, plasmid isolation, transformation, quantification of nucleic acids, cryopreservation

#### **ACTIVITES AND INVOLVEMENT**

## **Genetics Graduate Student Association**

Travel Award Committee Chair 2018

Georgia Junior Science & Humanities Symposium Paper Reader 2016, 2018

Clarke County Science and Engineering Fair

Science Fair Judge 2016, 2018

Clarke Middle School

Reptile Education Assistant 2017

2017 National Science Bowl

Timekeeper/Rules Judge 2017

**Genetics Graduate Student Association** 

Social Chair 2016 - 2017

**Genetics Graduate Student Association** 

Travel Award Reviewer 2016

Athens Science Observer

Blog Contributor 2016

American Society of Naturalists

Member 2016 – present

Society for the Study of Evolution

Member 2016 - present

**Genetics Society of America** 

Member 2018 - present

 Placed mice on platforms inside boxes atop arduinos that transmitted the startle reflex of a mouse in response to a loud noise to the computer

- Developed vocalization recordings from mouse vocalizations using Adobe Audition
- Trained new undergraduate research assistants on basic laboratory techniques

### **EDUCATION**

### **DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY (PH.D.) IN GENETICS**

University of Georgia

Dissertation Title: Genomic and Transcriptomic Impacts of Largeand Small-Scale Spontaneous Mutations in Yeasts

# BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S.) IN CELL AND MOLECULAR BIOLOGY

University of South Florida

Thesis: Ultrasonic Mouse Vocalizations Facilitate the Acoustic Startle Reflex in Male CBA/CaJs

### **PUBLICATIONS**

In prep

**McQueary, H**, M. Behringer, S. Demario, A. Canas, B. Johnson, A. Tsfoni, J. Chamberlin, D. Hall. Effects of spontaneous aneuploidy on gene expression in yeast mutation accumulation lines

### SELECTED PRESENTATIONS

**Talk Titled:** "Effects of Ploidy and Transposon Load on Mutation Rate in Saccharomyces paradoxus"

GENE 8880, Department of Genetics, University of Georgia, 2019 **Talk Titled:** "Effects of Differing Transposon Load on Mutation Rate in Saccharomyces paradoxus"

Southestern Population Ecology and Evolutionary Genetics Meeting, Clemson Outdoor Lab, SC, 2019

#### AWARDS/HONORS

# **Genetics Graduate Student Association Travel Award**

2019

Department of Genetics

### SEPEEG Travel Award

2019

American Society of Naturalists

# Mary E. Case Award for Excellence in Teaching

2018

Department of Genetics

## Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award

2018

Graduate School, University of Georgia

# Robin Hightower Graduate Support Fund

2018

Department of Genetics, University of Georgia

### Graduate Travel Award for Submission of NSF GRFP Proposal

2016, 2017

Graduate School, University of Georgia

#### Rosemary Grant Award

2016

Society for the Study of Evolution

**Talk Titled:** "Gene expression in aneuploid yeast"

GENE 8880, Department of Genetics, University of Georgia, 2018 **Poster Titled:** "Effects on Gene Expression of Spontaneous Aneuploidy in Yeast Mutation Accumulation Lines"

Southestern Population Ecology and Evolutionary Genetics Meeting, Mountain Lake Biological Station, VA, 2018

**Talk Titled:** "Evolution of Dosage Compensation in Saccharomyces cerevisiae"

3MT Competition, University of Georgia, Athens, GA, 2016 **Poster Titled:** "Rates and Biases of Mitotic Gene Conversion in Saccharomyces cerevisiae"

Evolution, Austin, TX, 2016

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

### **Graduate Teaching Assistant,** Evolutionary Biology

2019

- Lead discussion sections once per week and hold office hours
- Upload quizzes and exams for internet-based testing

### **Graduate Teaching Assistant,** Introductory Genetics. 2017 – 2018

- Lead 2 discussion sections per week for 45 students, and hold office hours during the week
- Grade and proctor exams during the semester for 300 students

### Graduate Teaching Assistant, Biology I for Non-Majors 2017

- Coordinate assignments and material for an online course
- Grade assignments and give feedback

### Graduate Laboratory Assistant, Biology I for Non-Majors 2016 – 2017

- Lead 3 laboratory classes per week for 20 students, assist students during labs
- Grade assignments and hold office hours